<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ML/DL Engineering on Kyle van de Langemheen</title><link>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/categories/mldl-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in ML/DL Engineering on Kyle van de Langemheen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/categories/mldl-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Another Attempt at Embedding Apps</title><link>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/streamlit-test2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/streamlit-test2/</guid><description>&lt;iframe
src="https://vaatzes-nerve-growth-sim.hf.space"
frameborder="0"
width="100%"
height="450px"
style="background:none transparent;"
allowtransparency="true"
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description></item><item><title>Embedding a Dynamic WebApp</title><link>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/streamlit-test/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/streamlit-test/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/streamlit-test/streamlit.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Embedding a Dynamic WebApp" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is a first attempt at getting Streamlit apps embedded on this webpage. If you&amp;rsquo;re unsure why this is amazing, let me explain the difference between static pages and dynamic ones. Intuitively, a static page is the same for every visitor, supports only limited interactivity, and is stored as-is on the server. It loads quickly and is so easy to host that it is completely free on many platforms. That way, to get a personal website like this one, you&amp;rsquo;d only need to pay for the DNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic pages are a bit different. There are server-side computations going on and served to the webclient in real-time. Typically all websites that do a bit more than just offering pages to read, such as social media platforms, e-shops, personalized user pages, and any interactivity beyond that would require dynamic content. This server has to perform more computations than just picking out the right files to send, and so usually require more set-up and come at a price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By being able to embed dynamic content on a static page, the dynamic content can be hosted elsewhere and the interactivity still served to your website. Think for example of showing YouTube videos or ads on your webpage. The external content is loaded in dynamically when a user visits your site, while the internal content is displayed as-is. This is especially important for me because many of the projects I would want to showcase on my website require AI models or interactive data visualizations. The &lt;a class="link" href="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/pac-winrate/" &gt;PAC Winrate&lt;/a&gt; plot for example was directly exported as code, and the data is hardcoded in with the page. The &lt;a class="link" href="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/" &gt;Nerve Growth Simulation&lt;/a&gt; is actually in 3D but I found no way to host an interactive 3D plot with this many datapoints on a static page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through embedding this content, I can show more (and more fun!) content in an interactive format, close to what the project is actually about. In this post I will be showcasing an example webapp I built as part of another application process. The model was already provided, the task was to do a code review on it, demo it with a webapp, and propose a future, improved, and more complete architecture. Here is the webapp in action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe
src="https://floralpina-demo.streamlit.app?embed=true"
style="height: 450px; width: 100%;"
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oops! Not all features integrate as nicely. Most notable, the callbacks for authentication breaks when running in embedded mode. Furthermore, it does not respond to the light/dark mode toggle on my website. Finally, if the page is unused for a while, Streamlit takes the container that runs the app down. This means the server essentially has to be restarted for the next visitor, which can take 5-10 minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s very likely that this has happened to you just now (and then you got disappointed that you cannot login&amp;hellip;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s the solution? Well, the easiest answer is: Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it. Running and hosting Streamlit apps is essentially free for my usecase, so it should be fine even without authentication. The light/dark mode is a bit of a pain, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll look at having a transparent background (that can dynamically be applied when running in embedded mode?). But it is by no means a dealbreaker. And it is the same with launching the app. Sure, it takes some time. But the project is there and can be easily accessed, even if it takes some waiting. For now, that is sufficient. If there&amp;rsquo;s ever a need to move a project to be permanently available, I can always just spin up an instance on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Micro-imaging Segmentation at Nanolive</title><link>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/nanolive-optuna/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/nanolive-optuna/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/nanolive-optuna/cells.png" alt="Featured image of post Micro-imaging Segmentation at Nanolive" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="me-and-nanolive"&gt;Me and Nanolive
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between 2022 and 2023 I spend just over half a year at the startup &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nanolive.ch" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Nanolive&lt;/a&gt;, a startup bringing a unique approach to cell biology. Traditional microscopy typically separates acquisition and analysis as two separate steps, but Nanolive combines them into a unified, AI-powered solution. Advanced image analysis with (pre)trained ML/DL models often suffer if the image acquisition procedure is systemically different from that seen in the training data. Digital image analysis solutions often have to work on a wide range of noise signatures, optical aberrations, resolution differences, and much more. Nanolive&amp;rsquo;s 2-for-1 package addresses this by standardizing the microscopy process, creating a robust platform for the included downstream analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the Deep Quantitative Biology team, Nanolive&amp;rsquo;s core R&amp;amp;D team, one of my core responsiblities was to develop an optimization platform. The team has exclusive access to their own wet lab and utilizes a combination of fluorescent labeling and manual labeling / label correction on an ih-house labelling platform to train cutting-edge segmentation models. The optimization platform was to take in previously existing models and data, and to then explore subsamples, settings, and hyperparameter space, to optimize our models and automatically generate performance reports. This allowed us to identify potential weaknesses of our models, but also to spend labelling efforts only where they would be most impactful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="their-publication"&gt;Their Publication
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I was thrilled to see my old team&amp;rsquo;s latest publication: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-49260-7" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Dynamic label-free analysis of SARS-CoV-2 infection reveals virus-induced subcellular remodeling&lt;/a&gt;. Their unique position in the field allowed them to reach findings few other labs could: using Nanolive&amp;rsquo;s label-free methodology, high quantities of live cells can be analyzed over a much longer period of time than competing technologies. Let&amp;rsquo;s summarize who contributed, what their findings are and why this is valuable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="who"&gt;WHO
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.pasteur.fr/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Pasteur Institute&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Virus &amp;amp; Immunity Unit and &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nanolive.ch/about/company/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Nanolive&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Deep Quantitative Biology team. Together, they bring strong virology expertise and a high-throughput, label-free methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="what"&gt;WHAT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The authors analyze how SARS-CoV-2 impacts subcellular structures and internal cell dynamics, showing how the virus modifies cells to boost its own production and delay the host’s immune response. They further demonstrate the robustness of their ML segmentation despite the numerous challenges with establishing a ground truth in this space. This is then used to compare the organelle dynamics over two days for infected samples and non-infected control cells. Anyone familiar with the field will be aware that measuring hundreds of live cells over this large time-span while quantifying sub-cellular dynamics is a feat on its own! The authors further identify time-windows of the numerous effects of SARS-CoV-2 on the infected host, resolving conflicts in the existing literature. Finally, Bayesian networks for infected cells compared to control classes, show that SARS-CoV-2 strongly affects the process through which lipid droplets are produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how"&gt;HOW
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standard microscopy either lacks resolution or damages live cells, but Nanolive’s holotomography (HT) creates a 3D refractive index tomogram. This process, conceptually similar to a CT scan, yields high resolution output without damaging the cell. Nanolive is the first company to make microscopy solutions based on the HT principle commercialy available. Normally, staining or other markers would have to be added to label cells. Unfortunately, this damages the cell and can influence the inner cell dynamics. Manual labelling effort would be required to avoid using damaging agents, but this human involvement typically limits the amount of cells that can be quantified and analyzed. By using ML-based segmentation, hundreds of living cells and subcellular dynamics can be tracked over hours and even days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="why"&gt;WHY
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the subcellular changes during SARS-CoV-2 infection sheds light on its lifecycle and clarifies previously conflicting data by showing it varies over time. This paper is a big step forward in high-throughput, high-resolution analysis of cellular dynamics and demonstrates the potential of Nanolive’s innovative approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working alongside my former colleagues at Nanolive was truly a privilege. They’re some of the most dedicated, talented, and genuinely pleasant people I’ve had the opportunity to meet. Their commitment to pushing the boundaries of cell biology at Nanolive shines through in this latest publication. It’s rewarding to see even a small part of my work contribute to such impactful findings. I’m confident that with their skills and vision, there’s a bright future ahead for the team and the field of high-resolution, high-throughput cell analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Header image adapted from &lt;a class="link" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Human_mesenchymal_stem_cells.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>