<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on Kyle van de Langemheen</title><link>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/categories/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on Kyle van de Langemheen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3D "Nerve growth" Simulation</title><link>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/nerves1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post 3D "Nerve growth" Simulation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of a job application I was asked to consider features for a 3D scan of the subepidermal nerve plexus. However, rather than just looking through the literature, I thought it would be fun to also implement some of them. Unfortunately at this stage in the application process, I do not yet have access to the data. So I thought to generate my own!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has various benefits, the predominant one that we can use the simulation to understand our features better. Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have a feature which describes the branching factor of the nerves. Then for a certain volume inside the scan (our real data), we find that the branching factor is 0.45. What does this mean? With a simulation, we could visually describe &amp;amp; interpret our features. We can have a progression from 0. to 1. branching factor, giving a much more obvious feeling for what a branching factor of 0.45 means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simulation is a vast oversimplification, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to expand on. As of now, we can control things like thickness, spread &amp;amp; growth direction, and how much it branches. In the future I would like to add additional simulation options such as bundling of multiple fine nerves, and better controls for visualization. Either way, this is enough to at least get a first look at what the simulation looks like!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/nerves1.jpg"
width="626"
height="565"
srcset="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/nerves1_hu_aaa3e32fd7d82ae1.jpg 480w, https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/nerves1_hu_a845c9e98a37e0cb.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Nerves grow towards the blue dots. Note that this is actually in 3D!"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="110"
data-flex-basis="265px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/nerves2.jpg"
width="593"
height="551"
srcset="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/nerves2_hu_da700490714da34d.jpg 480w, https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/application-usz/nerves2_hu_1fe25dacf7a0c46d.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Results of a completed simulation. Some dots are not reachable."
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="107"
data-flex-basis="258px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My implementation is roughly based on &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/jasonwebb/2d-space-colonization-experiments" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;this implementation of space colonization in 2D&lt;/a&gt;. As you can see, it has a very nice &amp;ldquo;natural&amp;rdquo; feel to it, although it&amp;rsquo;s still far from realistic nerve growth. Still, it should suffice for a proof of concept of some features to describe 3D nerve topology!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Micro-imaging Segmentation at Nanolive</title><link>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/nanolive-optuna/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/nanolive-optuna/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://kylevdlangemheen.com/p/nanolive-optuna/cells.png" alt="Featured image of post Micro-imaging Segmentation at Nanolive" /&gt;&lt;h2 id="me-and-nanolive"&gt;Me and Nanolive
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between 2022 and 2023 I spend just over half a year at the startup &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nanolive.ch" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Nanolive&lt;/a&gt;, a startup bringing a unique approach to cell biology. Traditional microscopy typically separates acquisition and analysis as two separate steps, but Nanolive combines them into a unified, AI-powered solution. Advanced image analysis with (pre)trained ML/DL models often suffer if the image acquisition procedure is systemically different from that seen in the training data. Digital image analysis solutions often have to work on a wide range of noise signatures, optical aberrations, resolution differences, and much more. Nanolive&amp;rsquo;s 2-for-1 package addresses this by standardizing the microscopy process, creating a robust platform for the included downstream analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the Deep Quantitative Biology team, Nanolive&amp;rsquo;s core R&amp;amp;D team, one of my core responsiblities was to develop an optimization platform. The team has exclusive access to their own wet lab and utilizes a combination of fluorescent labeling and manual labeling / label correction on an ih-house labelling platform to train cutting-edge segmentation models. The optimization platform was to take in previously existing models and data, and to then explore subsamples, settings, and hyperparameter space, to optimize our models and automatically generate performance reports. This allowed us to identify potential weaknesses of our models, but also to spend labelling efforts only where they would be most impactful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="their-publication"&gt;Their Publication
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I was thrilled to see my old team&amp;rsquo;s latest publication: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-49260-7" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Dynamic label-free analysis of SARS-CoV-2 infection reveals virus-induced subcellular remodeling&lt;/a&gt;. Their unique position in the field allowed them to reach findings few other labs could: using Nanolive&amp;rsquo;s label-free methodology, high quantities of live cells can be analyzed over a much longer period of time than competing technologies. Let&amp;rsquo;s summarize who contributed, what their findings are and why this is valuable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="who"&gt;WHO
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.pasteur.fr/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Pasteur Institute&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Virus &amp;amp; Immunity Unit and &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nanolive.ch/about/company/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Nanolive&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Deep Quantitative Biology team. Together, they bring strong virology expertise and a high-throughput, label-free methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="what"&gt;WHAT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The authors analyze how SARS-CoV-2 impacts subcellular structures and internal cell dynamics, showing how the virus modifies cells to boost its own production and delay the host’s immune response. They further demonstrate the robustness of their ML segmentation despite the numerous challenges with establishing a ground truth in this space. This is then used to compare the organelle dynamics over two days for infected samples and non-infected control cells. Anyone familiar with the field will be aware that measuring hundreds of live cells over this large time-span while quantifying sub-cellular dynamics is a feat on its own! The authors further identify time-windows of the numerous effects of SARS-CoV-2 on the infected host, resolving conflicts in the existing literature. Finally, Bayesian networks for infected cells compared to control classes, show that SARS-CoV-2 strongly affects the process through which lipid droplets are produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how"&gt;HOW
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standard microscopy either lacks resolution or damages live cells, but Nanolive’s holotomography (HT) creates a 3D refractive index tomogram. This process, conceptually similar to a CT scan, yields high resolution output without damaging the cell. Nanolive is the first company to make microscopy solutions based on the HT principle commercialy available. Normally, staining or other markers would have to be added to label cells. Unfortunately, this damages the cell and can influence the inner cell dynamics. Manual labelling effort would be required to avoid using damaging agents, but this human involvement typically limits the amount of cells that can be quantified and analyzed. By using ML-based segmentation, hundreds of living cells and subcellular dynamics can be tracked over hours and even days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="why"&gt;WHY
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the subcellular changes during SARS-CoV-2 infection sheds light on its lifecycle and clarifies previously conflicting data by showing it varies over time. This paper is a big step forward in high-throughput, high-resolution analysis of cellular dynamics and demonstrates the potential of Nanolive’s innovative approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working alongside my former colleagues at Nanolive was truly a privilege. They’re some of the most dedicated, talented, and genuinely pleasant people I’ve had the opportunity to meet. Their commitment to pushing the boundaries of cell biology at Nanolive shines through in this latest publication. It’s rewarding to see even a small part of my work contribute to such impactful findings. I’m confident that with their skills and vision, there’s a bright future ahead for the team and the field of high-resolution, high-throughput cell analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Header image adapted from &lt;a class="link" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Human_mesenchymal_stem_cells.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>